The house stood on a slight rise just on the edge of the village.
It stood on its own and looked out over a broad spread of west country farmland.
Not a remarkable house by any means.
It was about thirty years old, squatish, squarish, made of brick, and had four windows set in
the front of a size and proportion which more or less exactly failed to please the
eye.
The only person for whom the house was in any way special was Arthur Dent, and that was only
because it happened to be the one he lived in.
He had lived in it for about three years, ever since he had moved out of London because it
made him nervous and irritable.
He was about thirty as well, tall, dark-haired, and never quite at ease with himself.
The thing that used to worry him most was the fact that people always used to ask him
what he was looking so worried about.
He worked in local radio, which he always used to tell his friends was a lot more interesting
than they probably thought.
It was, too.
Most of his friends worked in advertising.
On Wednesday night it had rained very heavily.
The lane was wet and muddy, but the Thursday morning sun was bright and clear as it shone
on Arthur Dent's house for what was to be the last time.
It hadn't properly registered yet with Arthur that the council wanted to knock it down and
build a bypass instead.
At eight o'clock on Thursday morning, Arthur didn't feel very good.
He woke up blearily, got up, wandered blearily round his room, opened a window, saw a bulldozer,
found his slippers, and stomped off to the bathroom to wash.
Toothpaste on the brush, so scrub.
Shaving mirror, pointing at the ceiling, he adjusted it.
For a moment it reflected a second bulldozer through the bathroom window.
Properly adjusted, it reflected Arthur Dent's bristles.
He shaved them off, washed, dried, and stomped off to the kitchen to find something pleasant
to put in his mouth.
Kettle, plug, fridge, milk, coffee, yawn.
The word bulldozer wandered through his mind for a moment in search of something to connect
with.
The bulldozer outside the kitchen window was quite a big one.
He stared at it.
Yellow, he thought, and stomped off back to his bedroom to get dressed.
During the bathroom, he stopped to drink a large glass of water, and another.
He began to suspect that he was hungover.
Why was he hungover?
Had he been drinking the night before?
He supposed that he must have been.
He caught a glint in the shaving mirror.
Yellow, he thought, and stomped onto the bedroom.
He stood and thought.
The pub, he thought.
Oh, dear, the pub.
He vaguely remembered being angry, angry about something that seemed important.
He'd been telling people about it, telling people about it at great lengths, he rather
suspected.
His clearest visual recollection was of glazed looks on other people's faces, something
about a new bypass he'd just found out about.
It had been in the pipeline for months, only no one seemed to have known about it.
He took a swig of water.
It would sort itself out, he decided.
No one wanted a bypass.
The council didn't have a leg to stand on.
It would sort itself out.
God, what a terrible hangover it had earned him, though.
He looked at himself in the wardrobe mirror.
He stuck out his tongue.
Yellow, he thought.
The word yellow wandered through his mind in search of something to connect with.